<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <title>Data Manager</title>

  <chapter>
    <title>Requirements</title>

    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>

      <para>This document outlines the requirements for the Data Manager
      application built on the ACS 5.2 platform.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Vision Statement</title>

      <para>Most of object implied in the learning process can and should be
      reused, may be another time or may be in another computer. Data Manager
      package allows you to move .LRN objects from one class of community to
      another one. It also provides de possibility of export an object to a
      file and import it into another .LRN instance.</para>

      <para>Once a class or community is designed, this is, taks to be
      resolved and objects that takes part into this tasks, next step is to
      put all this events into the plattform. Obviously, it must be done by
      the administrator or the professor, while the student is just an
      spectator.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Historical Considerations</title>

      <para>Since the aim of this package is to move and copy objects created
      by another packages, and to do this from a unique interface, here is a
      brief list of several objects and the task allowed by them.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Faqs: A faq can be disabled and enabled later. When a faq is
          disabled it does not appear in the community home, but it continue
          belonging to this community. You can also delete a Faq, but with
          this you don't delete any data from the database and neither you can
          recover the erased object.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>News: You can tag a New as archived, but it does not means
          that the object has been moved or deleted.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Forums: As wells as faqs, a forum can be disabled and enabled.
          A forum cannot be deleted.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Assessment: The assessment package provides de functionality
          to export and import to an QTI file.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>User portlet:</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>File Storage Folders: A single file can be moved, copied and
          deleted. A folder can be deleted. When a item is deleted, it cannot
          be recovered.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Aplication Overview</title>

      <para>Datamanager package does not create new tables into data model,
      because it does not need any persistent data. The main task of the
      aplication is to provide a unique interface to move and copy objects,
      which implies that the database values must be modified.</para>

      <para>That means: this package does not need its own tables in the data
      model, but it has the functionality of changing the values of tables
      created for another packages.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Use Cases and Scenarios</title>

      <para>Involved roles are administrator and profesor, and tipical use
      cases in which datamanager can be used are:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A profesor has done a mistake, so he has created an object
          into another community. He does not want just to delete this object,
          he would want to move it to the correct community.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>An object has been created, but it has been an error. The
          tipical procedure is to delete this wrong object or to move it to a
          invisible place.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The period of a class has been finished, and the profesor want
          to reuse the objects in the next period or class. Here, the desired
          issue is to be able of copying objects, so the ended class can be
          archived without changes and the new one has all the required
          contents. Tipically, only the object root is needed. This is,
          avoiding to copy all the students comments. Despite of this, the two
          scenarios can take place.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The platform will be instaled in a newer computer, or a new
          release of the platform leads the administrator to a migration of
          the system. In this case, the administrator can export objects to an
          xml file and later he will import them into the new instance of the
          platform.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A platform has a really interesting object, so it is desirable
          to use this objects into another platforms, or just to store it into
          a file and place this file into a file server. With this, you allow
          another profesors to improve his own platforms using your
          interesting contents. In this case, the profesor will export the
          object to an XML file.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>User Interfaces</title>

      <para>Data Manager package only can be used by professors and
      administrators, so there are two different interfaces. Both of them are
      linked form the administration page (/dotlrn/control-panel).</para>

      <section id="professor_interface">
        <title>Professor Interface</title>

        <para>A professor is able to move, copy, delete, export and import
        objects.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Move</term>

            <listitem>
              <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of objects from which the professor has
                  permissions.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a way to select objects from this list.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of communities or classes where the
                  object will be moved.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a confirmation page.</para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Copy</term>

            <listitem>
              <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of objects from which the professor has
                  permissions.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a way to select objects from this list.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of communities or classes where the
                  object will be copied.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a confirmation page.no </para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Delete</term>

            <listitem>
              <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of objects from which the professor has
                  permissions.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a way to select objects from this list.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a confirmation page.</para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Export</term>

            <listitem>
              <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of objects from which the professor has
                  permissions.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a way to select objects from this list.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Allow to choose the filename.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a confirmation page.</para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Import</term>

            <listitem>
              <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Allow to select a XML local file.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of communities or classes where the
                  object will be imported.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a confirmation page.</para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Administrator Interface</title>

        <para>All the requirements listed at <xref
        linkend="professor_interface" />, and the capability to recover data
        from the Trash.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Recover</term>

            <listitem>
              <orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of objects stored in the Trash.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a way to select objects from this list.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a list of communities or classes where the
                  object will be stored..</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Provide a confirmation page.</para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Desing tips</title>

    <section>
      <title>Essentials</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>User directory: /datamanager/</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>TCL procedures: /datamanager/tcl/datamanager-procs.tcl</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>This document:
          /datamangar/www/doc/datamanager_spec.html</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Introduccition</title>

      <para>Data Manager package aims to provide a centralized interface which
      allow users to move, copy, export and import objects.</para>

      <para>Main tips related with the aplication desing are exposed
      here.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>API</title>

      <para>The API will be defined during the development phase.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Acceptance Test</title>

      <para>Regresion test will be implemented to check all the
      functionalities.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Future Improvements</title>

      <para>The first release is designed to work with forums, faqs,
      assessment, news, folders and user portlets. </para>

      <para>Next releases will implement the same features for all the objects
      in the platform.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Authors</title>

      <para>Please, mail suggestions or bug reports to Luis de la Fuente
      (<email>lfuente@it.uc3m.es</email>).</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Revision History</title>

      <informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="4">
          <thead>
            <row>
              <entry>Document revision</entry>

              <entry>Action Taken</entry>

              <entry>Date(dd/mm/yyyy)</entry>

              <entry>Author</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>0.1</entry>

              <entry>Creation</entry>

              <entry>24/06/2005</entry>

              <entry>Luis de la Fuente</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry></entry>

              <entry></entry>

              <entry></entry>

              <entry></entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>